Guide to the Dr. Eric F. Rhodes papers, 1934-2004 MS2323
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Dr. Eric F. Rhodes papers
1934-2004
1940-1945
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Rhodes, Barbara
Rhodes, Eric F., 1927-
MS2323
0.5 Linear Feet
This collection cointains correspondence, photographs, publications, certificates, and ephemera. This material was produced by Dr. Eric Rhodes during his lifetimea and relates to his professional as well as personal life. From 1940-1947 Dr. Rhodes attended junior high school and high school years in Washington DC. Most of the records in the collection relate to this time period. Rhodes attended Langley Junior High School and McKinley High School and then received three advanced degrees from GWU. There is a small amount of material related to Dr. Rhodes' time working with the National Education Association and the Educational Service Bureau and also some material related to his life as an author of short fiction and poetry. These records cover 1934-2004 with the bulk covering from 1940-1945.
Biographical / Historical
Eric Foster Rhodes (1927-2012) was born Feburary 5, 1927 in Luray, VA. He attended Langley Junior High School and McKinley High School in Washington DC. During his time in high school he was involved with the Tech Dramatic Club, Saber Club, and served as a Captain in the Washington High School Cadet Corps. Following service in the Army during WWII, he earned his bachelor's, master's and doctorate degrees at George Washington University. The graduate degrees came from the Graduate School of Education where he taught as a part-time adjunct professor for 12 years. His career involved working in various positions and consulting for educational agencies and systems in 37 states. In the 1960s, he was hired by the state of Virginia to conduct work that ultimately led to the development of the master plan for 22 colleges with 35 campus sites that today forms the Virginia Community College System. As an independent consultant, and president of Educational Service Bureau, Dr. Rhodes published 16 non-fiction books, primarily on organization and management of schools and colleges. For a time he was also Director of Employee Relations for the City of Orlando.
In addition to his professional work in the field of education, Dr. Rhodes volunteered on a civil rights commission, as a counselor to senior victims for a police department and as an advisory chairman for Keep America Beautiful. He was a member and past president of the Unitarian-Universalist Church of Tarpon Springs. Dr. Rhodes also wrote novels and poetry include publishing his writings including mystery novels, short stories, humorous essays and books of poetry.
Dr. Rhodes died at the age of 85 August 24, 2012 in New Port Richey, Florida.
Separated Materials
The following books have been removed from the collection and placed in the Special Collections stacks.
Authored by (or with contributions from Eric F. Rhodes) America Sings Silent Sarenade Pantoums Going home for Christmas 24 stories set in the Christmas season Dusting off dreams Skull Session a "Jeep" Winston Mystery The Octopus murders a "Jeep" Winston Mystery This Time a colletion of poems Remembering a collection of poems I saw a door in Dublin and other poems Et Cetera a collection of stories Ouch! I'm shot in the knuckle humor, columns, and cartoons Where the heart is and other poems Then and now a collection of poems Making good things happen negotiating for a better life (with Ricahrd G. Neal)
Works not by Eric Rhodes: The command performance by Jack Stuart Knapp The giants' stair a play in one act by Wilbur Daniel Steele The Day after forever a one-act comedy-drama by Charles Emery Come out of the kitchen by A.E. Thomas When alters burn a one-act play for four females by Kay Arthur The old lady shows her medals a play in one act by J. M. Barrie The Fan: a comedy in three acts by Goldoni translated by Henry B. Fuller
The Techite of '44 (McKinley High School year book) The Techite of '45 (McKinley High School year book)
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Barbara Rhodes, January 3, 2014 (2014.001)
Scope and Contents
This collection cointains correspondence, photographs, publications, certificates, and ephemera. This material was produced by Dr. Eric Rhodes during his lifetimea and relates to his professional as well as personal life. From 1940-1947 Dr. Rhodes attended junior high school and high school years in Washington DC. Most of the records in the collection relate to this time period. Rhodes attended Langley Junior High School and McKinley High School and then received three advanced degrees from GWU. There is a small amount of material related to Dr. Rhodes' time working with the National Education Association and the Educational Service Bureau and also some material related to his life as an author of short fiction and poetry. These records cover 1934-2004 with the bulk covering from 1940-1945.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
Rhodes, Barbara; National Education Association of the United States
- The Adjutant Washington High School Cadets, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Army, 1946-1949 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  General
  Related to Eric Rhodes' time in the Army including mess hall and other passes, photographs, correspndence, and order schedules.
- City Teachers Association proposed legislative program from 1963 program (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 2010, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Eric Rhodes biographical ephemera, 1934-2003 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Educational Services Bureau, inc, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Griffith Stadium miliary parade, Circa 1945 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  These may be images of the Cadet Corps for McKinley High School.
- Keep American Beautiful, inc, 1968, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Langley Junior High School, 1940-1944 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Includes report cards.
- McKinley High School records, 1937-1945 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- McKinley High School Guard of Honor for General Eisenhower, 1945 June 14 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- McKinley High School 20th and 30th reunions for June 1946-Feb. 1947 class, 1966 June 10 - 1975 April 12 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- McKinley High School Saber Club, 1944 November 15 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- McKinley High School Tech Life student newspaper, 1942-1945 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- McKinley High School class photograph, 1945 June (Box SHARED Box 27, Box Original Individual Box 2, Folder Original Folder 1)
- National Education Association [NEA], 1959-2004 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Photographs and postcards, Circa 1945 - Circa 1990, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  The images include people and buildings. None of the images has identification, but several are Eric Rhodes.
  Please note: there are other images in other folders.
- Published poems by Eric Rhodes, 1994 October - 1995 Spring (Box 1, Folder 17)
  from The Rockford Review and Tradition bi-monthly poetry publication
- Testimonials for Eric Rhodes, 1969-1994 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Washington baseball club offical score cards, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 19)